<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: security | Prateek Gianchandani]]></title>
  <link href="http://prateek147.github.io//categories/security/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://prateek147.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2014-12-03T18:11:24+04:00</updated>
  <id>http://prateek147.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Prateek Gianchandani]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Damn Vulnerable iOS App v1.4 launched]]></title>
    <link href="http://prateek147.github.io/2014/12/01/damn-vulnerable-ios-app-v1-dot-4-launched"/>
    <updated>2014-12-01T18:07:00+04:00</updated>
    <id>http://prateek147.github.io/2014/12/01/damn-vulnerable-ios-app-v1-dot-4-launched</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I am so excited to release the latest version of <a href="http://damnvulnerableiosapp.com">Damn Vulnerable iOS app.</a> Up till now, DVIA has been downloaded more than 75000 times and i can&rsquo;t wait for the count to reach 6 digits :&ndash;)</p>

<p>Following vulnerabilities and challenges have been added in the latest version.</p>

<ol>
<li>Sensitive information in memory<li>
<li> Webkit Caching (Insecure data storage)<li>
<li>Certificate pinning bypass <li>
</ol>


<p>You can download the latest version from <a href="http://damnvulnerableiosapp.com/#downloads">here</a>.
The source code is available on the project&rsquo;s github page <a href="https://github.com/prateek147/DVIA">here</a>.</p>

<!-- more -->




<h3>Manual Installation</h3>


<p>Download the .ipa file from the <a href="http://damnvulnerableiosapp.com/#downloads">downloads</a> page, change its name from DamnVulnerableiOSApp.ipa to DamnVulnerableIOSApp.zip and unzip this file. This will unzip to a folder named Payload. Inside it, there will be a file named DamnVulnerableIOSApp.app. Then copy the .app file to the /Applications directory on the device using Scp. You can also use sftp or the utility iExplorer to upload this application.</p>

<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/dvia/1.png" width="1126" height="510" alt="1"></p>

<p>Now login as the mobile user, use the command su to get root privileges and give the DVIA binary executable permissions. Then use the exit command to go back as the mobile user, and use the command uicache to install the application. If this doesn’t work, you can reboot the device or try this method again.</p>

<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/dvia/2.png" width="799" height="284" alt="2"></p>

<p>To compile the application, you should follow the instructions mentioned <a href="http://damnvulnerableiosapp.com/2013/12/get-started/">here</a>.</p>

<p>Any commits to the source code on Github or suggestions to improve the app are welcome.</p>

<p>Special thanks to <a href="http://twitter.com/crylico">@crylico</a> to help test the application before release.</p>

<p>Happy hacking !</p>

<p>-Prateek</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Android Application hacking with Insecure Bank Part 1]]></title>
    <link href="http://prateek147.github.io/2014/11/24/android-application-hacking-with-insecure-bank-part-1"/>
    <updated>2014-11-24T00:52:00+04:00</updated>
    <id>http://prateek147.github.io/2014/11/24/android-application-hacking-with-insecure-bank-part-1</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In this article series, we will learn at various concepts of Android application security while exploiting a vulnerable app InsecureBankv2. We will be looking at all the concepts from a noob's perspective and hence i would recommend this blog series to beginners as well.</p>




<p>However, the first thing to do is set up a proper mobile pentesting platform for android application testing.</p>




<p>The first thing to do is download the Eclipse ADT bundle. You can then follow the instructions <a href="https://developer.android.com/sdk/installing/index.html?pkg=adt">here</a> to install the ADT bundle. Once this is done, make sure you install the necessary sdk packages and libraries by following the instructions <a href="https://developer.android.com/sdk/installing/adding-packages.html">here</a>.</p>




<!-- more -->




<p>Inside the adt bundle folder and inside the sdk folder, there will be two folders, one with the name <i>tools</i> and the other with the name <i>platform-tools</i>. It's important to add the location of your SDK platform tools and tools folder to the PATH environment variable. This is because you will be using most of the command line tools included in these directories and its good to have them added in the path environment variable. The command to add any path as an environment variable is <i>export PATH=/path/to/dir:$PATH</i>.</p>


<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/ib1/1.png" width="725" height="146" alt="1"></p>

<p>Do this for both the tools and the platform-tools folder. Once this is done, you can access all the command line tools without actually browsing over to their directory. To check if this is working, type the command <i>adb</i> and see if you are able to get an output like this.</p>


<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/ib1/2.png" width="728" height="417" alt="2"></p>

<p>To run the application on your computer, it is important to have a good emulator. Now the android virtual device manager utility in Eclipse allows you to create your own emulators. To know how to create these virtual devices, i would recommend you check <a href="https://developer.android.com/tools/devices/index.html">this</a> article out. However, for this series, i am going to be using Genymotion to create my own emulators. There are many reasons for this. First of all, it is lightning fast and not as slow as the android emulators. Secondly, it is a rooted emulator unlike the android emulators. This means you have much more freedom of installing your own custom applications that can be used for auditing other android apps. </p>




<p>Once you install genymotion, you should sign up for a new account (it's free) and create different emulators based on your need. Here is what my emulators look like.</p>


<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/ib1/3.png" width="798" height="427" alt="3"></p>

<p>Now get the latest code for the InsecureBankv2 application from <a href="https://github.com/dineshshetty/Android-InsecureBankv2">here</a>.</p>


<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/ib1/4.png" width="1046" height="137" alt="4"></p>

<p>Start one of your genymotion emulators and see if you are able to get them running. Starting an emulator is as simple as clicking on the play button.</p>


<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/ib1/5.png" width="1070" height="618" alt="5"></p>

<p>Inside the folder that you just cloned from github, there will be an apk file. You can install that application onto your emulator using the command <i>adb install InsecureBankv2.apk</i></p>


<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/ib1/6.png" width="939" height="134" alt="6"></p>

<p>You will see that it successfully installed. And you can see the same on the emulator as well. But sometimes you might want to compile the application rather than run it with an apk file. To do that, open Eclipse and go to <i>File -> Switch Workspace</i>, and choose the Insecure bank folder that you just created. Now go to <i>File -> Import</i> and select <i>Existing Android code into workspace</i>.</p>


<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/ib1/7.png" width="525" height="551" alt="7"></p>

<p>Select your application folder and you will see that Eclipse will import the application into your workspace. Now click on the play button on the top to run your application. Make sure your genymotion emulator is running as well. Select to run it as an android application.</p>


<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/ib1/8.png" width="851" height="586" alt="8"></p>

<p>You will see that the application starts successfully on the genymotion emulator.</p>


<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/ib1/9.png" width="1066" height="574" alt="9"></p>

<p>Also start the backend python server that the android application communicates with using the command <i>python app.py --port 8888</i></p>


<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/ib1/10.png" width="726" height="81" alt="10"></p>

<p>In the application, go to Preferences and enter the IP address and port number of your system.</p>


<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/ib1/11.png" width="612" height="472" alt="11"></p>

<p>And now you can login to the application using the default credentials.</p>




<ul>
<li>dinesh/Dinesh@123$</li>
<li>jack/Jack@123$</li>
</ul>




<p>Also make sure that you install the following utilities. We will cover them in detail as and when they are required.</p>




<ol>
    <li><a href="https://www.mwrinfosecurity.com/products/drozer/">Drozer</a></li>
    <li><a href="https://github.com/swdunlop/AndBug">Andbug</a></li>
    <li><a href="https://github.com/iSECPartners/Introspy-Android">Introspy</a></li>
    <li><a href="https://code.google.com/p/dex2jar/">dex2jar</a></li>
    <li><a href="https://code.google.com/p/android-apktool/">apktool</a></li>
</ol>




<p>Also, connect to your emulator using the command <i>adb shell</i> and see what are the things you can do. I would really recommend you to have a look <a href="http://developer.android.com/tools/help/adb.html">here</a> and try out all the commands possible with the Android debug bridge.</p>




<p>Another thing that you can read up is what you can do with all the command line tools available in Android. You can read it from <a href="http://developer.android.com/tools/projects/projects-cmdline.html">here</a>. In the next article, we will start at actual exploitation of the InsecureBankv2 application.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[iOS Application Security Part 36 – Bypassing certificate pinning using SSL Kill switch]]></title>
    <link href="http://prateek147.github.io/2014/11/03/ios-application-security-part-36-bypassing-certificate-pinning-using-ssl-kill-switch"/>
    <updated>2014-11-03T01:00:00+04:00</updated>
    <id>http://prateek147.github.io/2014/11/03/ios-application-security-part-36-bypassing-certificate-pinning-using-ssl-kill-switch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In this article, we will look at how we can analyze network traffic for applications that use certificate pinning. One of the best definitions i found of certificate pinning is mentioned below. It is taken directly from <a href="https://www.infinum.co/the-capsized-eight/articles/securing-mobile-banking-on-android-with-ssl-certificate-pinning">this</a> url.</p>




<p>
By default, when making an SSL connection, the client checks that the server’s certificate:</p>




<ul>
<li>has a verifiable chain of trust back to a trusted (root) certificate</li>
<li>matches the requested hostname</li>
<li>What it doesn't do is check if the certificate in question is a specific certificate, namely the one you know your server is using.</li>
</ul>




<!-- more -->


<p>Relying on matching certificates between the device&rsquo;s trust store and the remote server opens up a security hole. The device’s trust store can easily be compromised &ndash; the user can install unsafe certificates, thus allowing potential man-in-the-middle attacks.</p>

<p>Certificate pinning is the solution to this problem. It means hard-coding the certificate known to be used by the server in the mobile application. The app can then ignore the device’s trust store and rely on its own, and allow only SSL connections to hosts signed with certificates stored inside the application.</p>

<p>This also gives a possibility of trusting a host with a self-signed certificate without the need to install additional certificates on the device.
</p></p>

<p>Certificate pinning is used by many popular applications for e.g Twitter, Square etc. So the question that arises is, how do you bypass this certificate validation that is happening on the client side ? The important thing to note here is all that all the validation is happening on the client side. And since there are frameworks like Mobile Substrate that allow us to patch any method during runtime and modify its implementation, it is possible to disable the certificate validation that is happening in the application.</p>




<p>A POC tool for this by released in Blackhat and it was named iOS SSL Kill Switch. The full presentation can be found <a href="https://media.blackhat.com/bh-us-12/Turbo/Diquet/BH_US_12_Diqut_Osborne_Mobile_Certificate_Pinning_Slides.pdf">here</a>. After some time, the author realized that he was able to inspect traffic from apps that used certificate pinning (for e.g Twitter), but he wasn't able to see the traffic going through the App Store app. He then realized he needed to patch even more low level methods and kill specific processes in order to inspect traffic going via the App store app. The full writeup for this could be found <a href="https://nabla-c0d3.github.io/blog/2013/08/20/intercepting-the-app-stores-traffic-on-iOS/">here</a> and it's quite interesting, so i suggest you give it a read. Also note that this tool will also be able to disable the default SSL certificate validation, so you don't need to install a certificate as trusted root as well, which is what we usually do for inspeting traffic over HTTPs.</p>




<p>To really check that the Twitter app uses certificate pinning, install the Twitter app and route the device traffic through Burp Proxy. Make sure you are inspect traffic via HTTP/HTTPS using the steps mentioned in <a href="http://highaltitudehacks.com/2013/08/20/iOS-application-security-part-11-analyzing-network-traffic-over-http-slash-https">Part 11</a> of this series. However, when you open the twitter app and navigate around, the traffic is not captured by Burpsuite.</>




<p>To inspect the traffic going via Twitter, ssh into your device and download the iOS SSL Kill Switch package from it's <a href="https://github.com/iSECPartners/iOS-ssl-kill-switch/releases">releases</a> link. Also, make sure to install the following packages via Cydia.</p>




<ul>
<li>dpkg</li>
<li>MobileSubstrate</li>
<li>PreferenceLoader</li>
</ul>




<p>Now install the deb package using the command <i>dpkg -i <packagename></i>.</p>


<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/ios36/1.png" width="967" height="134" alt="1"></p>

<p>Now, respring the device using the command <i>killall -HUP SpringBoard</i>.</p>




<p>Once this is done, go to Settings app. There will be a new menu for SSK Kill Switch and a slider to Disable certificate validation. Make sure the slider is set to on.</p>


<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/ios36/2.png" width="832" height="254" alt="2"></p>

<p>Now route the traffic in the device to pass through Burp Proxy. Open twitter app and now you can see all the data going through via the twitter app as well.</p>


<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/ios36/3.png" width="1045" height="451" alt="3"></p>

<p>To verify that SSL Kill Switch is being injected into the application, go to Xcode -> Devices (I am using Xcode 6), look for your device in the left menu and click on the arrow pointing up in the lower left corner to see the device logs. You will see that SSL Kill Switch is being injected into the application.</p>


<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/ios36/4.png" width="598" height="123" alt="4"></p>

<p>Another cool utility that does the same job is <a href="https://github.com/intrepidusgroup/trustme">trustme</a>. I recommend you check it out.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wifite Walkthrough part 2: Cracking WPA access points]]></title>
    <link href="http://prateek147.github.io/2014/10/27/wifite-walkthrough-part-2-cracking-wpa-access-points"/>
    <updated>2014-10-27T01:43:00+04:00</updated>
    <id>http://prateek147.github.io/2014/10/27/wifite-walkthrough-part-2-cracking-wpa-access-points</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In this article, we will look at cracking access points using WPA-PSK or WPA2-PSK using Wifite.</p>




<p>If you have used tools like airodump-ng, aircrack-ng etc to crack WPA access points before, you would know that the required thing to successfully crack a WPA-PSK network is a captured WPA four-way handshake. More details about the WPA four-way handshake can be found on <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IEEE_802.11i-2004">this</a> wikipedia page.</p>




<p>As mentioned in the previous article, there is a bug in Wifite that may or may not be there in your particular version of Wifite. The bug basically doesn't aireplay-ng to function properly and displays an error like <i>aireplay-ng exited unexpectedly </i>. In order to fix this, you will have to make slight modifications in the code of wifite. You can install gedit (apt-get install gedit) which is a text editor and then edit the wifite python script (found in /usr/bin/wifite) using the steps mentioned <a href="https://code.google.com/p/wifite/issues/detail?id=127">here</a>. To open wifite, use the command <i>gedit /usr/bin/wifite</i>. This will open up the source code of wifite. Then replace every occurence of <i>cmd = ['aireplay-ng',</i> with <i>cmd = ['aireplay-ng','--ignore-negative-one',</i></p>




<!-- more -->




<p>To start wifite for cracking a WPA access point, give it the option <i>-wpa</i> to only target WPA networks. Also, give it a dictionary file as an input for cracking the WPA passphrase with the <i>-dict</i> option. In kali linux, the wordlists are stored at the location <i>/usr/share/wordlists</i>. Wifite will now start scanning for WPA access points.</p>


<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/wifite2/1.png" width="947" height="316" alt="1"></p>

<p>Press Ctrl+C to give a target number. In my case, the target number is 2 which is an access point i have configured for testing purposes. The access point uses WPA2-PSK encryption with the key as "password".</p>


<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/wifite2/2.png" width="741" height="443" alt="2"></p>

<p>Wifite will now start listening for the handshake. Once it has found it, it will automatically start cracking the passphrase using the dictionary file that we supplied.</p>


<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/wifite2/4.png" width="834" height="358" alt="4"></p>

<p>And as you can see, Wifite has successfully found the passphrase for the access point.</p>




<p>Sometimes, things may not work as smoothly. In order to capture a WPA handshake between the client and the access point, the client has to connect to the wireless network during that period when we are monitoring the network. If the client is already connected, there will be no handshake that is captured. Wifite does this by automatically sending deauthentication packets to a particular client or a broadcast deauthentication packet if it is required. You can specify the time between deauthentication packets using the -wpadt flag. Hence, when the client tries to reconnect to the access point, the handshake is captured.</p>




<p>You can also specify which tool you want to use to crack the passphrase once the four-way handshake has been successfully captured. By default, aircrack-ng is selected. You can also use cowpatty, pyrit or tshark to crack the passphrase.</p>


<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/wifite2/5.png" width="622" height="92" alt="5"></p>

<p>Another cool option in Wifite is to anonymize your MAC address using the <i>-mac</i> option. Even though it is quite trivial using simple commands or <i>macchanger</i> utility to change the MAC address for a specific interface, it is good to have this feature in the tool itself. However, in order to make this work, you first have to take that specific interface for which you want to change the MAC address down to managed mode if it is in monitor mode previously. You can use the command <i>iwconfig</i> to check all the interfaces that are in monitor mode and then take them down using the command <i>airmon-ng stop interface-name</i> command. As we can see from the image below, the mon0 interface is in monitor mode.</p>


<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/wifite2/6.png" width="698" height="287" alt="6"></p>

<p>Hence, lets take it down using the command <i>airmon-ng stop mon0</i></p>


<p>.</p>

<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/wifite2/7.png" width="678" height="351" alt="7"></p>

<p>Now we can add the <i>-mac</i> option to anonymize the MAC address. As you can see, Wifite is intelligent enough to change the MAC address to something that is similar the existing MAC address of the interface and not to something ridiculous (for e.g AA:BB:CC:DD:EE:FF) which is a giveaway.</p>


<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/wifite2/8.png" width="895" height="378" alt="8"></p>

<p>And when you stop the capture, Wifite is nice enough to change the MAC address back to the original one.</p>




<p>In this article, we looked at how we can use Wifite to crack networks using WPA-PSK or WPA2-PSK. Wifite is great at its job and automates almost everything, however it is important to understand how it uses the tools like airodump-ng, aircrack-ng etc under the hood to perform its task. I would recommend that you go through the source code of Wifite and figure out how this is done.</p>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Wifite Walkthrough part 1: Cracking WEP access points]]></title>
    <link href="http://prateek147.github.io/2014/10/27/wifite-walkthrough-part-1-cracking-wep-access-points"/>
    <updated>2014-10-27T01:41:00+04:00</updated>
    <id>http://prateek147.github.io/2014/10/27/wifite-walkthrough-part-1-cracking-wep-access-points</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>In this article series, we will look at a tool named Wifite suitable for automated auditing of wireless networks. Most of you who have experience in wireless pentesting would use tools like airmon-ng, aireplay-ng, airodump-ng, aircrack-ng to crack wireless networks. This would involve a sequence of steps, like capturing a specific numbers of IV's in case of WEP, capturing the WPA handshake in case of WPA etc, and then subsequently using aircrack-ng to crack the password required for authentication to the network. Wifite aims to ease this process by using a wrapper over all these tools and thus making it super easy to crack Wifi networks.</p>




<p>Here is a list of features of Wifite as per its official <a href="https://code.google.com/p/wifite/">homepage</a>.</p>




<ul>
    <li>sorts targets by signal strength (in dB); cracks closest access points first</li>
    <li>automatically de-authenticates clients of hidden networks to reveal SSIDs</li>
    <li>numerous filters to specify exactly what to attack (wep/wpa/both, above certain signal strengths, channels, etc)</li>
    <li>customizable settings (timeouts, packets/sec, etc)</li> 
    <li>"anonymous" feature; changes MAC to a random address before attacking, then changes back when attacks are complete</li>
    <li>all captured WPA handshakes are backed up to wifite.py's current directory</li>
    <li>smart WPA de-authentication; cycles between all clients and broadcast deauths</li>
    <li>stop any attack with Ctrl+C, with options to continue, move onto next target, skip to cracking, or exit</li>
    <li>displays session summary at exit; shows any cracked keys</li>
    <li>all passwords saved to cracked.txt</li>
    <li>built-in updater: ./wifite.py -upgrade</li>
</ul>




<!-- more -->




<p>Before we start using wifite, make sure you have a proper wireless card that supports packet injection. If you don't have one, i would suggest that you buy <a href="http://www.amazon.com/Alfa-AWUS036H-802-11b-Wireless-network/dp/B002WCEWU8">this</a> card.</p>




<p><p>Note that there is a bug in Wifite that may or may not be there in your particular version of Wifite. The bug basically doesn&rsquo;t aireplay-ng to function properly and displays an error like <i>aireplay-ng exited unexpectedly </i>. In order to fix this, you will have to make slight modifications in the code of wifite. You can install gedit (apt-get install gedit) which is a text editor and then edit the wifite python script (found in /usr/bin/wifite) using the steps mentioned <a href="https://code.google.com/p/wifite/issues/detail?id=127">here</a>. To open wifite, use the command <i>gedit /usr/bin/wifite</i>. This will open up the source code of wifite. Then replace every occurence of <i>cmd = [&lsquo;aireplay-ng&rsquo;,</i> with <i>cmd = [&lsquo;aireplay-ng&rsquo;,&lsquo;&mdash;ignore-negative-one&rsquo;,</i></p>

<p><p>Wifite can be found under <i>Applications &ndash;> Kali Linux &ndash;> Wireless Attacks &ndash;> 802.11 Wireless Tools</i>. Also, note that if you are running wifite in a different VM than Kali Linux, then you have to make sure that tools like airmon-ng, aireplay-ng, airodump-ng, aircrack-ng are already installed on that system. This is because Wifite is nothing but a wrapper over all these tools. Before we even start using Wifite, it is better to update to the latest version.</p></p>

<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/wifite1/1.png" width="846" height="328" alt="1"></p>

<p><p>In my case, i already have the latest version. In this tutorial, we will be targeting a simple Wifi network with WEP encryption. Just using the command <i>wifite -h</i> will give you a list of all the commands.</p></p>

<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/wifite1/2.png" width="962" height="596" alt="2"></p>

<p><p>A very tempting option would be <i>-all</i> which tries to attack every network that it finds. We will try it in later articles in this series. However, first lets take a look at all the targets that we have. To do that, use the command <i>wifite -showb</i></p></p>

<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/wifite1/3.png" width="930" height="331" alt="3"></p>

<p><p>Once this is done, we can see that wifite has put our network interface card into monitor mode (using airmon-ng) and started to look for clients. After a few more seconds, it will start displaying the list of access points.</p></p>

<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/wifite1/4.png" width="907" height="314" alt="4"></p>

<p><p>Note that as it is mentioned in its feature list (automatically de-authenticates clients of hidden networks to reveal SSIDs), this list will also include hidden access points. Hence, wifite can also be used to find hidden access points. In this case we will attack an access point with the BSSID 00:26:75:02:EF:65 that i have set up for testing purposes. The access point has a simple WEP password <i>1234567890</i>.</p></p>

<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/wifite1/5.png" width="777" height="290" alt="5"></p>

<p><p>To start attacking an access point, just press <i>Ctrl+C</i>. Wifite will now ask you to choose a target number from the list. The target number for my test network is 1, so let me enter that. Note that if you press <i>Ctrl+C</i> again, it will quit Wifite.</p></p>

<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/wifite1/6.png" width="750" height="80" alt="6"></p>

<p><p>You can now see that Wifite will start attempting to crack the WEP access point using the different known techniques for cracking WEP encryption. After some unsuccessful tries, it has finally begun to start attacking the access points using different techniques for cracking WEP.</p></p>

<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/wifite1/11.png" width="744" height="160" alt="11"></p>

<p><p>Once enough IV&rsquo;s are being captured, it will automatically start cracking the password.</p></p>

<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/wifite1/12.png" width="653" height="324" alt="12"></p>

<p><p>As we can see, Wifite has successfully figured out the WEP key for the access point. Wifite is an extremely useful tool for cracking wireless networks. As i mentioned previously, you need to have all the tools like airmon-ng, aireplay-ng, airodump-ng, aircrack-ng already installed on your system. To further prove the point, let&rsquo;s dive into the source code of Wifite.</p></p>

<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/wifite1/10.png" width="545" height="297" alt="10"></p>

<p><p>As we can see, the python code has mentions of calling aireplay-ng. Hence, it is recommended to run Wifite inside Kali linux.</p></p>

<p><p>In the next article, we will look at some advanced usage options of Wifite.</p></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
