<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: octopress | Prateek Gianchandani]]></title>
  <link href="http://prateek147.github.io//categories/octopress/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://prateek147.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2018-04-19T16:29:28+04:00</updated>
  <id>http://prateek147.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Prateek Gianchandani]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Octopress: Category pages with preview and pagination]]></title>
    <link href="http://prateek147.github.io/2013/06/30/octopress-category-pages-with-preview-and-pagination"/>
    <updated>2013-06-30T02:27:00+04:00</updated>
    <id>http://prateek147.github.io/2013/06/30/octopress-category-pages-with-preview-and-pagination</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So i have been playing around with Octopress for a few weeks now and i love it. While creating this site, i bumped into a small problem.</p>

<h3>How do i display a category page with a preview of all the blog posts and include pagination in it as well ?</h3>


<p>Ofcourse, if you just want to visit the default category page that Octopress creates, you can just append something like <code>/categories/[category_name]/</code> to the base url. For e.g <a href="http://prateek147.github.io/categories/security">here</a> is the link to the posts with the category security. But this is so boring. It would have been cool to have a preview of each post just like the home page, and that also had pagination, something like <a href="http://prateek147.github.io/security">this</a> .</p>

<p>Here is how i did it.</p>

<p> <!-- more --></p>

<p>First of all, create a new page that will serve all the posts for that category. Let&rsquo;s assume that category name is <code>Travel</code>.</p>

<p>```
Prateeks-MacBook-Pro:octopress prateekgianchandani$ rake new_page[&ldquo;security&rdquo;]
mkdir -p source/security
Creating new page: source/security/index.markdown</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>Then go to <code>source/index.html</code> inside your Octopress directory. It would look something like this.</p>

<p>``` html</p>

<p>  {% include_code index.html %}</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>The only change that needs to be done is that instead of iterating over all the pages, we will have to iterate over the posts of a specific category. So basically you replace <code>paginator.posts</code> with <code>site.categories.security</code> where security is the category name. Here is how it will look like.</p>

<p>``` html</p>

<p>{% include_code security.html %}</p>

<p>```</p>

<p>Copy this code inside <code>security/index.markdown</code> file.</p>

<p>Now, your category page will be available at /security :)</p>

<p>Here is how it looks like on this site <a href="http://highaltitudehacks.com/security/">http://highaltitudehacks.com/security/</a></p>

<p>If you have any questions, feel free to ask them in the comments section below.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
