<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: honeypots | Prateek Gianchandani]]></title>
  <link href="http://prateek147.github.io//categories/honeypots/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://prateek147.github.io/"/>
  <updated>2015-12-19T14:56:14+04:00</updated>
  <id>http://prateek147.github.io/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Prateek Gianchandani]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ghost USB Honeypot Part 2 - Installing and running the honeypot]]></title>
    <link href="http://prateek147.github.io/2013/06/15/ghost-usb-honeypot-part-2-installing-and-running-the-honeypot"/>
    <updated>2013-06-15T04:42:00+04:00</updated>
    <id>http://prateek147.github.io/2013/06/15/ghost-usb-honeypot-part-2-installing-and-running-the-honeypot</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This article is in continuation of <a href="http://resources.infosecinstitute.com/ghost-usb-honeypot/">Part 1</a> of the series on Ghost USB Honeypot. Malware threats have become very common these days and hence the need of honeypots to detect those malwares have become equally important. In the last few years, we have seen how USB based malwares can be used to target highly protected machines that are not connected to the internet. In order to detect malwares that spread over USB devices, the Ghost USB Honeypot project was started. Ghost is a honeypot for detecting malware that spreads via USB devices. The honeypot currently supports Windows XP and Windows 7. The way Ghost works is that it first tries to emulate a USB thumb drive. If the malware identifies the emulated device as a USB thumb drive, it will try to infect it. Ghost then looks for write requests to the drive, which is an indication of a malware.</p>




<!-- more -->




<p>In the first part of this article, we covered an interview with the project leader Sebastian Poeplau. In this article we will be discussing how to install and use the honeypot on a windows machine to capture any data or binaries that the malware will install on your USB drive.</p>




<h2>Installing Ghost Honeypot</h2>




<p>Ghost USB honeypot currently runs only over Windows XP and Windows 7. A quick install guide for it could be found <a href="http://code.google.com/p/ghost-usb-honeypot/wiki/InstallGuide">here</a>. We will however be discussing it in this article too. The first step in this process is to install the ghost honeypot from its official webpage. A link to the binary package can be found <a href="http://code.google.com/p/ghost-usb-honeypot/downloads/list">here</a>. The next step is to install the 2 required dependencies. These are</p>




<p><p><b>a) Windows Driver Framework (WDF)</b>&ndash; More information about it and download links can be found <a href="http://msdn.microsoft.com/en-us/library/windows/hardware/gg463268.aspx">here</a>. Once you have downloaded and installed it, there are two files which you will need to copy to the folder where you downloaded Ghost. The default location for these files are <i>&ldquo;C:\Program files\Windows Kits\8.0\redist\wdf\x86\WdfCoInstaller01009.dll&rdquo;</i> and <i>&ldquo;C:\Program files\Windows Kits\8.0\redist\wdf\x86\WUDFUpdate_01009.dll&rdquo;</i> as shown in the figure below. These 2 files should be copied inside the folder where you have downloaded Ghost.</p>

<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/ghost-usb2/1.png" width="1366" height="768" alt="1"></p>

<p>b)<b>.NET Framework version 4 or higher</b>&ndash; Ghost also has a GUI version. If you want to install and run it on your system, then you need to have .NET framework version 4 or more installed on your system. You can download it from <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/en-in/download/details.aspx?id=17851">here</a>.</p>

<p><p>Now go to the folder where you downloaded Ghost and run Setup.exe. You may get warnings from the OS about installing these new drivers as shown in the image below. Ignore them and proceed with the installation.</p></p>

<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/ghost-usb2/2.png" width="1366" height="768" alt="2"></p>

<p><p>As discussed previously, what Ghost does is emulate a USB flash drive. Some of the key points while emulating a USB flash drive is to make sure that it is recognized as &ldquo;removable&rdquo; by the Windows OS. This is because a lot of malwares will write data only to removable devices. The Ghost tool does this very accurately by installing some specific drivers to do the task. What the Ghost tool also does pretty well is write all the data that was supposed to be written to the USB device onto a image file. This way, that image file can then be copied onto another system and used for analyzing the changes that were made to that image, like copied binaries or some other malicious code.</p></p>

<p><h2>Running the Honeypot</h2></p>

<p><p>Once you have installed the Ghost tool onto your system, you can either use it in the command line mode or the GUI mode.Note that the emulated USB flash drives will require image files. These image files have a predefined location, i.e C:\gd[0-8] when using the command line tool or C:\gdgui when using the GUI tool. Ghost will automatically create empty image files if they are not present. But these empty image files require formatting before they could be used. And hence a more better solution is to download preformatted image files from the project&rsquo;s website. The links could be found <a href="http://code.google.com/p/ghost-usb-honeypot/downloads/list">here</a>.Once you have downloaded these preformatted image files, you should rename them properly and place it at the appropriate location. For example, an example location for one of the image files could be C:\gd0.img for the command line tool and C:\gdgui.img for the GUI version.</p>

<p><p>We will start by using the command line version of Ghost first. To use it just go the directory where it is installed and
type &ldquo;ghosttool&rdquo;. One of the most important things to remember while doing this is to make sure that you are running command prompt as the system administrator, otherwise you will get an error.</p></p>

<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/ghost-usb2/5.png" width="670" height="353" alt="5"></p>

<p><p>Lets mount a virtual USB flash drive.</p></p>

<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/ghost-usb2/6.png" width="657" height="335" alt="6"></p>

<p><p>Once this is done, you will notice that you get a notification from windows that it has identified a usb device with removable storage. This makes sure that the device was emulated properly. Also, you can see that a removable device with capacity of about 100 mb is now being shown by Windows.</p></p>

<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/ghost-usb2/7.png" width="707" height="267" alt="7"></p>

<p><p>Now, if there is a malware installed on this system, it will detect this removable device and write data to this emulated USB device automatically. The binaries or data written to this USB will be captured in the image file, which could be then taken to a separate OS and used for analysis. In this case i will just copy some file to the usb device and when we unmount it, we will notice that Ghost has detected those write requests.</p></p>

<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/ghost-usb2/8.png" width="659" height="469" alt="8"></p>

<p><p>Now, we will have a quick look at the GUI version. Remember to run it as administrator. For the GUI version, the image file name will be gdgui.img. To mount an image, just click on Mount and it will emulate the USB device.</p></p>

<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/ghost-usb2/10.png" width="652" height="373" alt="10"></p>

<p><p>Once you unmount the device and if there was ever a write request to the drive, it will be shown to you as shown in the figure below.</p></p>

<p><img src="http://prateek147.github.io/images/posts/ghost-usb2/11.png" width="650" height="469" alt="11"></p>

<p><p>You can now copy the image file to a different isolated environment and use the captured data for analysis.</p></p>

<p><h2>Conclusion</h2></p>

<p><p>USB malwares are becoming more and more common these days. The ghost USB honeypot project aims at emulating a USB device to capture any data that a malware may write to your USB device. This captured data can then be transferred over to another system for analysis.</p></p>

<p><h2>References:</h2>
<ul>
<li><p>Ghost USB Honeypot project</br><a href ="http://http://code.google.com/p/ghost-usb-honeypot/"><a href="http://code.google.com/p/ghost-usb-honeypot/">http://code.google.com/p/ghost-usb-honeypot/</a></a></p>
</li>
</ul></p>

<p><p>This article was originally published on the <a href="http://resources.infosecinstitute.com/">resources</a> page at <a href="http://infosecinstitute.com/">Infosec Institute</a>. For more information, please visit my author <a href="http://resources.infosecinstitute.com/author/prateek/">page</a>.</p></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Ghost USB Honeypot Part 1- Interview with Project Leader Sebastian Poeplau]]></title>
    <link href="http://prateek147.github.io/2013/06/15/ghost-usb-honeypot-part-1-interview-with-project-leader-sebastian-poeplau"/>
    <updated>2013-06-15T04:05:00+04:00</updated>
    <id>http://prateek147.github.io/2013/06/15/ghost-usb-honeypot-part-1-interview-with-project-leader-sebastian-poeplau</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Malware threats have become very common these days. In the past, many honeypots have been created to detect malware propagation over the network. These honeypots trick the malware into believing that they are a part of the network. These honeypots are however isolated and once they have been infected, they can be used to study the behaviour of the malware. Network based malware have always been more successful, given the large number of systems they can affect in a short period of time.</p>




<!-- more -->




<p>These kind of network based malwares are however not able to infect systems that are isolated from the network. Such systems could contain highly confidential data. In the last few years, we have seen how USB based malwares can be used to target highly protected machines, i.e those which are not connected to the internet. This can allow these malwares to infect any system which supports plugging in of USB devices. One of the main examples of USB based malware is Stuxnet, a malware that used to spread via removable USB flash drives. In order to counteract the threat caused by USB based malware, the Ghost USB Honeypot project was created.</p>




<h2>Ghost USB Honeypot</h2>




<p>Ghost is a honeypot for detecting malware that spreads via USB devices. The honeypot currently supports Windows XP and Windows 7. The way Ghost works is that it first tries to emulate a USB thumb drive. If the malware identifies it as a  USB thumb drive, it will trick the malware into infecting it. Ghost then looks for write based requests on the drive, which is an indication of a malware. A good video about the project by Sebastian Poeplau can be found <a href ="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=9G9oo3b9qR4">here</a>.</p>


<p><b>Interview with Project Leader Sebastian Poeplau</b></p>

<p>The project is lead by Sebastian Poeplau, here is an interview with him about the Ghost USB Honeypot Project.</p>




<h3>1. Can you please start by telling us something about yourself, and how you got interested in malware research ?</h3>




<p>My name is Sebastian Poeplau, i am 22 years old and pursuing my studies in Computer Science from Bonn university, Germany. My interest with malware research began when i was working under a professor in second year of college and was offered some student assistantship. I liked this domain of security a lot and this is how it all began.</p>




<p>This article was originally published on the <a href="http://resources.infosecinstitute.com/">resources</a> page at <a href="http://infosecinstitute.com/">Infosec Institute</a>. For more information, please visit my author <a href="http://resources.infosecinstitute.com/author/prateek/">page</a>.</p>




<h3>2. Can you please tell us in brief about the the Ghost USB honeypot project?</h3>




<p>During the course of our research in malware analysis and detection, we realized that there was no such honeypot which detects malwares that spread over USB devices.  So me and my project members at the Computer Science department at Bonn university decided to create one on our own. Ghost works by first emulating a USB storage device, which tricks the malware into infecting the honeypot. Currently, Ghost only supports Windows XP and Windows 7, but we plan to port it to different versions of Windows, mainly because malwares generally target Windows based systems.</p>




<h3>3. What are the major challenges faced in performing malware analysis today?</h3>


<p></p>

<p>One of the major challenges is to be able to somehow analyze the huge amount of data that could be written to a honeypot to extract out the interesting bit of information. There are many good honeypots available that can capture the large amount of data, but there needs to be some kind of improvement in the current tools which could somehow help in automating the process of analyzing such a huge amount of data to get the interesting part.</p>




<h3>4. We have recently seen the emergence of some malwares that propagate over USB devices? This definitely helps the malware reach those systems that are not connected to the internet. Do you think there could be any other medium in the future over which malwares can propagate?</h3>




<p>I think there's just no need for malware authors to utilize another medium at the moment. These (network and USB) are the 2 major mediums over which malwares propagate. Also, since network based malwares have been so popular, i think we will see improvement in the way these malwares are created.</p>


<p></p>

<h3>5. Currently, the Ghost USB honeypot supports only Windows XP and Windows 7. Are there any plans to port it to other operating systems?</h3>




<p>Currently, we don't have any plans to make it available for other operating systems like Linux and Mac OS. This is mainly because USB malware are mainly created for Windows based operating systems. We do have plans to make it available for other remaining versions of Windows though.</p>




<h3>6. What were the major challenges that you faced while working on this project?</h3>




<p><p>One of the major challenges that i faced was to emulate USB storage devices. The api inside the windows kernel wasn&rsquo;t designed to emulate USB device. So i had to find a certain level within the layered architecture of the kernel where i can start to do the emulation. The problem is that the malwares should somehow be tricked into believing that the device is a proper USB device, i.e with removable capability. So i had to first emulate the USB device and then make sure that the malware identifies it as a proper storage device.</p>

<p><h3>7. Once the device is being emulated, how do you go about detecting the malware?</h3></p>

<p><p>It&rsquo;s simple. We just look for write requests. Any kind of write request without the user&rsquo;s permission is an indication of a possible malware.</p></p>

<p><h3>8. How far do you think has virtualization helped in facilitating the process of malware analysis? Also, where can we find samples of malware for testing purposes ?</h3></p>

<p><p>Virtualization has helped a lot. We no longer need a dedicated hardware to get infected with malware. It also helps in performing active analysis of the malware rather than just passive. This is because behaviour  of some of the malwares could only be analyzed in a live environment. <a href ="http://www.offensivecomputing.net/">Offensive Computing</a> has a good database of malwares that we can use for testing purposes. Also, people can now deploy their own honeypots in a virtual environment and use it for testing.</p></p>

<p><h3>9. What is the best way to stay in touch with the project?</h3></p>

<p><p>Keep checking the project <a href ="http://code.google.com/p/ghost-usb-honeypot/">homepage</a>. We post regular updates on it. Also, please feel free to get in touch with me at (Sebastian dot poeplau) on my gmail account. Also, you can follow by <a href="https://honeynet.org/blog/352">blog</a>.</p></p>

<p><ul>
<li><p>Ghost USB Honeypot</br><a href ="http://code.google.com/p/ghost-usb-honeypot/"><a href="http://code.google.com/p/ghost-usb-honeypot/">http://code.google.com/p/ghost-usb-honeypot/</a></a></p>
</li>
<li><p>Sebastian Poeplau&rsquo;s blog</br><a href ="https://honeynet.org/blog/352"><a href="https://honeynet.org/blog/352">https://honeynet.org/blog/352</a></a></p></li></p>

<p> </ul></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
